Now that we have, the n x n blocks for each one of the plains, the YCbC, we are
现在对应 YCbCr 的每个域 我们都有 n x n 的方块
ready to go into the forward transform. So the first thing we need to understand
现在我们进入正变换这一节 首先
is why are we going to do a forward transform.
我们需要了解为什么我们要做正变换
Let us explain first of all how do we measure the error that we create in
首先解释一下 在有损压缩时
images when we're doing compression if we're doing a lossy compression.
我们是如何量度压缩图像所产生的误差
And the basic idea is that error is measure with what's called the mean
基本想法是 误差是由均方误差 (mean square error)
squared error, MSE, or mean square error. And it's computed as following.
简称MSE 来量度的 均方误差是这样计算的
The mean squared error. Okay.
均方误差如下
MSE = 1 / the number of pixels. That just a normalization.
MSE=1/像素数目 这只是归一化
We sum overall the pixels and what we do is we basic compute the square of the
我们计算出每个像素上的误差的平方 并将所有的这些值相加
error. We have, we're going to have the
我们得到了重建的图像
reconstructed image, let's call it f, reconstruct it minus the
将其记为ḟ 用它减去原图像 再将差平方
original image squared. We go over every single pixel.
我们对每个像素计算
So we're going to do f. So let's say the, the original f was 100
现在我们计算 假定原来的 f是100
and we reconstructed 98, so we have the difference is 2 we square it, it's 4.
重建后是98 差值是2 平方后 我们得到4
And we do that for every single pixel. We sum that, we normalize that by the
我们对每个像素做此操作 全部加起来 然后用像素总数做归一化处理
number of pixels, and most of the time, because we have square here,
大部分时候 因为我们用了平方
we take a square root there. So it's called a root mean square error.
我们会取平方根 所以它被称为均方根误差
That's how we measure the error. Now, why are we going to do a transform?
这就是我们测量误差的方式 那么 为什么我们需要做变换呢
Let's imagine that we take, remember, we are talking n x n blocks
想象一下 我们取 n x n 的方块
now. In general, we're talking 8 x 8,
通常 我们取 8 x 8
but we're talking n x n. So we have n x n pieces,
但现在我们讲 n x n 的普遍情况 我们有 n x n 的方块
because we're working on each one of the blocks independently.
因为我们将对每个方块独立操作
Imagine that, although, these are n x n, 64 pixels, I
尽管有 n x n (n=8时 是64) 个像素
want to transmit only one. I'm going to just give you the option to
我只对其中一个进行传输 我允许你只传输其中一个
transmit only one of them. So, if we take just a regular image, and
那么 如果我们取一幅普通的图像
we transmit only one, we are going to get a tremendous error.
但只传输其中一个像素 误差将会非常大
But, we might be able to do a transform into a different 8 x 8, the transform has
但是 我们或许可以做一个变换 将其转为一个不同的 8 x 8 的方块
to be reversable, I should be able to go back.
这个变换需要是可逆的 必须可以恢复原状
And we do this transform, we have a new 8 x 8, and maybe in that transform domain,
我们做了这个变换 得到一个新的 8 x 8 的方块 或许在变换域
we can take only the first one and still do a reasonable job.
我们可以只取第一个元素 并且取得不太差的效果
It turns out that there is a transform that allow us to do that and that's
事实上 存在一个变换能有这效果
called the Karhunen-Loeve transform. [SOUND] That transformer has something
它是卡洛南-洛伊变换 (Karhunen-Loeve Transform) 即 K-L变换
very particular. You go into that transform domain, I'm
这个变换有一些很特别的地方 看这个变换域
going to write down in a second what do I mean by a transform?
我会马上写出来 变换是什么意思
But think is nothing else than a multiplication by a matrix,
但是想想看 其实就是乘以一个矩阵
nothing else than that. So I have my 8 x 8.
就是那样的操作 我有一个 8 x 8 模块
I do something. I go into a new 8 x 8 block or 8 x 8
做了一些操作 我得到一个新的 8 x 8 模块 也就是 8 x 8 的图像
image. And then, if what I did is a
那么假如我刚才做的是 K-L变换
Karhunen-Loeve transform, that's also sometimes written as KLT, Karhunen-Loeve
有时它也被写成 KLT 即卡洛南-洛伊变换
transform. If I'm in that domain,
假如在变换域中
if I take the first of those, just the first out of the 64 and I compute the
我取64个元素中的第一个
mean square error, remember, I basically did a reconstruction with only one.
然后计算均方误差 记住我刚才只用了一个元素去做重建
So I take my image, I do a Karhunen-Loeve transform.
我拿一幅图像 做 K-L变换
I remove 63 of the coefficients. I come back and I compute the mean square error.
我去掉了其中的63个系数 然后反变换 并且计算均方误差
I got the smallest possible mean square error I could have gotten with only one
我取得了在只用一个系数的情况下 可能的最小均方误差
basically coefficient, just transmitting only one.
只传输一个元素
If I want three, I can do actually exactly the same.
如果我想要3个元素 我可以做完全一样的事
ANd the interesting part with the Karhunen-Loeve transform is not only that
而 K-L变换 有趣的地方在于
with one I did the best error, but actually that one is the first one.
你不仅仅得到了在只用一个元素情况下最小的误差 而且那个元素是第一个
So you go, you have 64, you're gong to a new 64. You pick the first one, that's
所以可以想象 有64个元素 你会得到新的64个元素 取第一个
the best you can do if you're only allowed to use one coefficient.
那是你只能用一个元素的情况下 你能得到的最小误差
If you're allowed to, to use three, you pick the first three.
如果你可以用三个系数 那么就取前三个即可
So it's a great transform, but it has only one major problem.
所以这个变换很好 但是它有一个大问题
The problem of this transform is that it's image dependent.
这个变换是依赖于图像的
I don't know how to do it. So I told you, it's going to be a matrix
我一开始并不知道怎么操作 正如我刚才所说 这是一个矩阵乘法
multiplication, but I don't know the coefficients of the
但是在我看到图像之前 我不知道要乘的矩阵的系数
matrix until I don't see the image. You give me the image or you give me some
你先给我图像 或者关于图像的信息
information about the image, then I will be able to compute the
然后我才可以计算这个矩阵的系数
coefficients of that matrix. And that's not very practical,
这样实用性不强
it's very slow, and also, I cannot do things on the fly
这样很慢 而且 我不能一拿到图像就马上操作
as things come. So to replace that we count what's called
为了替代 我们采用一种
a discrete cosine transform, which is what is actually used in JPEG.
离散余弦变换 (discrete cosine transform) 这种变换是真正在 JPEG 中使用的
So let's just right down the equations for the discrete cosine transform and we
我们现在就写下离散余弦变换的公式
are going to understand a bit more of what a transform is.
我们接下来进一步解释下这个变换
But let's keep in our minds that what we actually want is a Karhunen-Loeve
但是要记住 我们其实是想要做 K-L变换
transform. What the Karhunen-Loeve is doing is decorrealating the image, it's
K-L变换所做的事情是 消除图像元素之间的相关性
putting a lot of information the first coefficient,
它把很多信息都放进了第一个系数
and a bit more of information in the second, which is independent of the first
然后更多一点的信息放进了第二个系数 两个系数间是相互独立的
and so on in such a way, that if we want to compute the means squared error, we
之后的系数以此类推 而且我们计算得到的均方误差是最优的
are optimal. But we're going to be suboptimal with the
但是用离散余弦变换 我们将会得到次优的结果
discrete cosine transform, but it's going to have a fixed matrix, fixed
但这个变换有一个固定的矩阵
coefficient, so it's universal, we're going to be able to use for every image
有固定的系数 所以是通用的 我们可以对任意图片使用
without having to recompute it. So what is a transform?
而不需要做额外计算 那么究竟什么是变换
The idea is very simple. We have an image and we can call this
想法很简单 我们有一张图像
image, let's say f(x, y) and this is a transform.
记之为 f(x,y) 来写下这个变换
We're going to go into a new domain T(u, v).
我们会进入一个新的变换域 T(u,v)
Okay? And those of you that are familiar with
你们中的一些人是熟悉傅里叶变换的
Fourier, Fourier is one of the transform. So we're going to sum overall the pixels
傅里叶变换就是一种变换 我们会将图像中所有的像素相加
in our image. Remember, we basically have n.
记住 我们有n个元素
So we are going to go from 0 to n - 1. We're going to go from 0 to n - 1 and
所以我们将从 0 操作到 n-1 这里也是从 0 操作到 n-1
we're going to take our image f and multiply by transform coefficient.
用图像 f(x,y) 乘以变换系数
This is what will become, I have to give you the formulas for what are these
这是我们将得到的 我必须给你
numbers for DCT, for the discrete cosine transform.
关于离散余弦变换 (DCT) 系数的公式
This will be completely image dependent for the Karhunen-Loeve.
对于K-L变换 这些系数完全依赖于图像
We not only depend on the positions we are, it will actually depend on the
不仅依赖于所取的位置
actual gray values on the actual statistics of your image.
还依赖于你图像上实际的灰度值
So this is a transforms. I sum over x and y, which means that x
这就是一个变换 我在 x和y 方向求和
and y will, let's say, disappear after my summation and I get a
那意味着 求和之后 x和y 都将消失
new image, which is again 8 x 8 or n x n. So this is n x n and it just in a
然后我得到一个新图像 是 8 x 8 或者 n x n 这是 n x n 的
transform domain and you can write this in matrix notation.
这是在变换域中 然后 你可以写成矩阵形式
Now, of course, a transform is only useful if you actually can invert it.
当然 一个变换只有在可逆的时候才有用
It won't be very nice that you give me an image.
如果你给我一幅图
I go into a transform domain that then visually I don't understand what's going
我进入变换域 但是视觉上我却看不懂 这就造成了不便
on there. So, there's also an inverse formula so I
所以还有一个逆变换公式
can get back f(x, y), it will be the sum from u = zero to n -
这样我可以回到f(x,y) 这将会是从u=0到n-1求和
1, the sum, from v = 0 to n - 1 of now my transform
以及 v=0到n-1 求和
coefficients, T(u,
变换系数 T(u,v)
v). And then the inverse of the transform, which we are going to write
然后是 逆变换 有时会等于 r
sometimes is equal to r sometimes is not, (x, y, u, v).
有时候不会 这里是 s(x,y,u,v)
So, I take an image, I do this operation, I get a new image in a transform domain,
如果我拿一幅图 进行这种操作 在变换域里得到一幅新图
and then I go and invert it. That's a transform.
然后继续 进行反变换
So, to specify the transform, I basically have to tell you, what are these guys?
为了说清什么是变换 我需要告诉你这些是什么
What's r and what's s? And once again, it's not hard to see and
r是什么？s是什么？ 再次说明 不难看出
you can just do this as an optional homework to write these in the matrix
你可以把这些写成矩阵形式 作为自选的作业
notation. It's not, not hard at all. So, I need to specify these two guys,
这一点也不难 现在我需要说明这两个是什么
these two functions, r and s, which as I say ideally to minimize the mean square
这两个函数 r和s 理想化情况下会使均方误差极小
to be optimal, we would like it to be Karhunen-Loeve transform but we can't, so
我们希望它是 K-L变换 但做不到
we are going to use the DCT, which I'm going to write next.
所以会使用DCT 接下来我会写出来
So what's the DCT? In the DCT, r(x, y, u, v) is actually
DCT是什么？在DCT中 r(x,y,u,v)
equal to s(x, y, u, v). And this is actually equal to some
实际上等于 s(x,y,u,v)
normalization coefficient alpha (u) alpha (v) this v and this v are the same.
这个实际上等于 归一化系数 α(u) × α(v) 这两个v是一样的
I, I apologize there for just writing two different vs.
抱歉我写了两个不一样的v
Cosine of the following, [(2x + 1) u pi / 2 * n], this is the
cos[(2x + 1) u π / (2n)]
size. Times cosine, exactly the same, but for
这是大小 乘上 完全一样但是是另外一个坐标
the other coordinate. 2y, [(2y + 1) v pi / 2n].
cos[(2y + 1) v π / (2n)]
That's a general formulation. And I have to basically write for you
这是通用公式 现在我将写下来
what's this, it's just a normalization. It's very common in this type of
这个是什么 这是归一化 在这类变换中很常见的
transforms, that the square root of 1 / n for u = 0 and the square root of 2 / n
当u=0时 对(1/n)求平方根
for u, different than 0.
当 u不为0时 对(2/n)求平方根
So here it is. I just gave you the formulas for DCT or
所以 我刚给出了DCT 即离散余弦变换的公式
the discrete cosine transform. Those that are familiar with Fourier,
对于熟悉傅里叶变换的人来说
this is basically the, the, basically the, the real part of a Fourier
这基本就是傅里叶变换的实部
transform. It's, it's almost that part.
几乎就是那个部分
So, once again, the forward transform and the backwards transform are exactly the
再说一次 正变换和逆变换在这里是一样的公式
same formulas. Very nice,
很好
because you need to build one piece of software or one piece of hardware to do
当你需要用软件或者硬件实现
both the forward and the backward and then it's just a cosine transform.
这些正变换和逆变换的时候 只要实现余弦变换就行了
Okay? So it's the cosine here and the cosine
所以这是余弦 这也是余弦
here and these are just normalization coefficients.
然后这些是归一化系数
This is the discrete cosine transform. Okay? Let's just see it.
这就是离散余弦变换
What, I want to see, I want to show you these functions.
我想要告诉你这些函数
These are the matrices that will multiply your image as we have seen in the
这些是我们在变换中 将用来和图像相乘的矩阵
previous slide, in order to get the transform.
正如之前所见
So here, you see actually, in this case just to make our illustration easy, we
这个例子中 为了使演示简单一些
use n = 4. So, these are, each one of the bases,
我们取n=4 对于每一个基函数
if I go back to the formulas and basically, I put u 0, = 0, I get a cosine
如果我用公式表达 当 u 和 v 都为 0 时 我得到一个余弦函数
which is a function of only x and y. The formulas were functions of u, v, x
这是一个仅关于x和y的函数 这些公式之前是关于u、v、x、y的函数
and y, but now I fix u and v,
但现在我固定u和v
I make both of them 0, I get a formula of x and y.
让 u和v 均为0 我得到一个只有 x和y 的公式
I get actually a 4 x 4 image which would be this.
这是我得到的 4 x 4 图像
If I basically fix v = 1 and u = 0, I get this and so on.
如果我让 v=1 且 u=0 我得到这个 以此类推
So basically this r and s are nothing else than what's called basis functions.
所以实际上 r和s 就是我们说的 基函数
And what we're trying to do is we're trying to decompose our small n x n image
而我们是在试着将 n×n 大小的小图像
into the linear combination of this basis functions.
分解成这些基函数的线性组合
So if your image is flat, it's going to have your T(u, v) is going to only be
如果是纯色图像 这里的T(u,v) 只要 u和v 的值都为0即可
known 0 for this. If your image has a lot of variations,
如果图像中变化频繁
you're going to have coefficients also for T(3, 3). So each one of the T(u, V)
那么你就需要一些系数 像 T(3,3) 这样  每一个 T(u,v)
tells you how much of this type of component you have.
都会描述你有多少这样的组成部分
Okay? So basically you have represented your n
现在我们已经用此类图像的线性组合
x n image into a linear combination of this type of images.
来表示 n × n 的图像了
The important part is that these images are constant.
很重要的一点是 这些图像是不变的
Again, in the Karhunen-Loeve, they won't be, and that's very difficult to have a
而我们提到过 在卡洛南-洛伊变换中它们并非如此
very efficient how our implementation to be able to do that in real time.
因此很难有高效的硬件实现可以实时完成那种变换
Here, this basis is fixed. You give me an image, I'm going to
而此处的基图像是固定不变的 你给我一张图
represent it as a linear combination of this basis.
我就会用这些基图像的一种线性组合来表示它
And T(u, v) tells me how much of each one of these I have in my image, in my
T(u, v) 也告诉我们 我们的图像里 要乘以的 n × n 图像里
timing, n x n image. So, that's a transform.
有多少这些基图像 这就是变换
Basically, nothing else than going into coefficient that tell us how much that
实际上这些系数最能告诉我们这些基图像
each one of these components. So I decompose my image into these
都包含了多少信息 我把图像
components which are kind of frequency components.
分解成这些分量 这些属于频率成分
You see that there is more variation as I increase v and as I increase u in the
可以看到 当u和v分别沿纵向和横向增大时
vertical or horizontal direction. There's one thing I haven't told you.
图像的变化更多了 有一点我之前没有告诉大家
I say, okay, I cant do Karhunen-Loeve transform, I cannot compute bases for a
我说过我们不能做卡洛南-洛伊变换 对于 K-L变换
Karhunen-Loeve because its too expensive, then I go and do a discrete cosine
计算其基函数太过繁复 因此我们进行离散余弦变换
transform. Why a discrete cosine transform? Why not
为什么选择离散余弦变换？
a Fourier transform or any other transform? How the mark transform? There
为什么不选择傅里叶变换或其他变换方法 譬如哈达玛变换 (Hadamard Transform)？
are many transforms out there. So there is a couple of reasons why we
变换方法有很多种 我们选择离散余弦变换有几个理由
use the DCT. One of them is that, although I want to
其一是 虽然我想进行卡洛南-洛伊变换
do a Karhunen-Loeve transform, I need to do a DCT.
我需要做离散余弦变换
It turns out that the DCT is for particular cases, actually exactly equal
其实在一些特定情况下 离散余弦变换
to the Karhunen-Loeve transform. Those particular cases are when the
完全等同于卡洛南-洛伊变换 这些特例中的图像
images what's called Markovian. So a pixel depends basically on the pixel
其像素排列符合马尔可夫链 即每个像素都以一种特殊的形式
next to it in a very particular form, and again, the pixel next to the pixel
依赖于相邻像素 然后相邻像素也是如此
next to it. So those are images that are called
以此类推 这就是所谓的一阶马尔可夫图像源
Markovian. So if you assume something about your
即 Markovian 如果可以设定一张图像
image, you can show that the Karhunen-Loeve transform ends up being
就可以证明卡洛南-洛伊变换最终就是离散余弦变换
the DCT. So it, at the end, it is a constant basis
所以最终 像我们这里看到的一样
like we see here. That's one reason and to basically decide
它的基图像是固定不变的 这就是我们使用离散余弦变换的一个原因
to use the DCT. The other reason that we use the DCT is
另一个我们使用离散余弦变换的
because of the following. Remember that I'm working from the whole
原因是这样的 我们是从整个图像着手操作的
image and basically having n x n blocks. Okay?
然后是这样的 n × n 的小块
Someone may wonder why not to use for example Fourier transform?
有人可能会疑惑为什么不用傅里叶变换之类的方法呢？
If we go back into the theory of Fourier transform, when you do a discrete Fourier
如果回去看傅里叶变换的理论 当我们进行离散傅里叶变换时
transform, you're making an underlying assumption of periodicity.
我们对周期性有一个潜在的假设
So you are basically assuming that your image repeats itself as we can see here.
我们是假设图像像我们看到的一样在自我重复
So this comes back here and this comes back here.
这一点在此处再次出现 而这一点则在这儿重复
Okay? So there is a repetition of your image.
所以这里图像在反复出现
That's the underlying mathematical assumption to be able to formally do a
有了这个潜在的数学上的假设
Fourier transform of this 8 x 8 block. And here, I'm drawing just one line of
我们才能真正地对 8 × 8 的小块进行傅里叶变换 在此 我只是标出了
the 8 x 8 block, but the same assumption basically goes in the other direction and
8 × 8 的小块中的一条线 但这个假设同样适用于每个方向
then in the two-dimensional. Now this this basically means that when
以及整个二维平面 也就是说我们处理完一个小块之后
your block ends, you're expecting the pixel in the next block to basically be
我们需要下一个小块中的像素
identical to the pixel that it was here. Okay? So you expect this block to
与这个小块的这个像素完全相同 即是说我们需要这个小块
basically repeats here and repeats here. That's your underlying assumption.
在这里和这里重复 这就是你的潜在的假设
It's not very probable that the pixel that was here is the same pixel value
这里和这里的像素一样的可能性很低
that was here, not even close in an 8 x 8 block maybe.
就算是在 8 × 8 小块中 这两个值可能也不接近
On the other hand, DCT assumes a different type of periodicity.
另一方面 离散余弦变换对周期性所作的假设是不同的
Basically DCT assumes that at the boundary, you have mirror symmetry.
离散余弦变换假设边界处有镜面对称
So basically, your image basically repeats,
即是说你的图像是在重复
but it kind of false. So, the assumption says, okay, I'm
但它可以说是翻折了 这个假设是说
assuming that the pixel here is similar to the pixel here right next to it.
假定这里的像素与相邻的这个像素类似
Note that the pixel is identical to the one that comes 8 pixels later, but just
不是说像素与八个像素之后的那一个相同
the pixel right next to it and that's a much more reasonable assumption.
而是与紧接着它的那个像素相同 这个假设更合理
So, those are two of the main reasons why we use a DCT.
这就是我们选用离散余弦变换的两个原因
One is because for certain types of images the DCT is the Karhunen-Loeve.
其一是对一类图像而言 进行离散余弦变换就是在进行卡洛南-洛伊变换
The other is because the periodicity, the type of the periodicity assumption is
其二是周期性 在我们从 n × n 或 8 × 8 小块开始处理图像时
much more applicable to images where we started by this n x n or 8 x 8 blocks.
离散余弦变换对周期性的假设更为实用
So now, we have the DCT. We started with an image.
现在我们知道离散余弦变换了 我们从一幅图像开始
We divided n x n blocks. We do a transform into a discrete cosine
将它分为 n × n 的小块 我们进行离散余弦变换
transform, where every coefficient tells us how much of this basis are we using.
所得的系数表明我们用到了多少基图像
I keep talking about 8 x 8. How we came to 8 x 8? Actually there was
我一直在讲 “8 × 8” 我们怎么得到 8 × 8 这个值的？
a lot of studies before jpeg was defined to get 8 x 8,
其实 JEPG 是在大量研究之后被设定为 8 × 8 规格的
but let me just illustrate what happens here.
我就解释一下这是怎么回事
This is an image that basically, we took the whole image.
这张图 我们取了整个图像
In this case, we don't divide. This is already a block of that image,
即是说我们没有做分割 这已经是我们提到过的
Lina, that we talked before. We did a discrete cosine transform of
Lena的图像的一块了 我们对整幅图
this entire block and we took 25% of the coefficient.
进行离散余弦变换 并取系数的25%
So we took basically only 1/4 of the coefficients, and we made everybody else
也就是说我们只取了四分之一的系数 并将其它系数设为零
0, and then we did the inverse, and that's the result that we got.
之后我们进行逆变换 这是我们得到的结果
We have introduced error and remember, basically, the DCT is, what it's going to
我们介绍过误差 记住离散余弦变换所作的是
try to do is going to try to bring us into a domain that introduce in error,
尽可能把我们引入一个变换域 这会产生误差
basically killing some of the coefficients making them 0 or making
因为在其中会去掉一些系数 将它们设为 0
errors on them, won't be as noticeable. But in this case, we did it very simple.
或引入一些差值 但只会造成很不显眼的误差 但这里我们做得很简单
We just took 25% of the DCT coefficients. Which ones is going very clear soon?
我们只取了 25%的离散余弦变换系数 我们很快会知道所取的系数是哪些
But just imagine that we took the, the 1/4 of the basically largest
但请先想象我们取了 1/4的值最大的那些系数
coefficients. Now, first we did it for the whole image.
首先我们是对整张图做处理
Here, we actually took only 2 x 2 blocks. So we went here and we divided in 2 x 2
这里我们只取 2 × 2 的小块 就是说我们这里把此图分割为 2 × 2 的小块
blocks and we need a DCT of every 2 x 2 and we took 25%..
我们对每个 2 × 2 小块进行离散余弦变换 然后取系数的25%
So be is, basically ended with only one and we came back.
所以我们最终只用了一个系数 然后逆变换
And you see this very, very annoying blocking artifact.
可以看到这个非常恼人的块效应
Then we did the same for 4 x 4 and we do the same for 8 x 8,
我们对 4 × 4 的分块方式 以及 8 × 8 的分块方式 分别做了同样的处理
And we see that basically its gets better and better.
我们看到图像效果越来越好
So, you might wonder, okay, 2 x 2 is too little,
也许大家会想 2 × 2 是太小了
but why to stop at 8 x 8? Why not to go to 16 x 16 and 32 x 32?
但为什么我们停在 8 × 8 ？ 为什么不选择 16 × 16 或 32 × 32 ？
And, and you know, why not to just do the DCT for the entire image?
或者为什么不对整幅图做离散余弦变换？
There's a couple of reasons for that. One is computational,
有这样几个原因 其一是计算方面的
the, basically it's cheaper to do multiple small DCTs than one large DCT.
进行多个小型离散余弦变换比一个大型变换更划算
So if you have a, let's say a 16 x 16 image, I'd rather do four 8 x 8 DCTs than
所以如果你有一个 16 × 16 的图像 对四个 8 × 8 小图进行离散余弦变换
doing just one 16 x 16 DCT. That's one of the reasons.
比对一个 16 × 16 大图做变换更方便 这是第一个原因
Another reason is this magic approximation of DCT to the
另一个原因是离散余弦变换与卡洛南-洛伊变换奇妙的相似性
Karhunen-Loeve. I say that happens under certain
我说过这发生在特定条件下
conditions, a Markovian condition.
即为一阶马尔可夫图像源时
If you're in a small region at 8 x 8 block,
如果你是在 8 × 8 小块里的一个小范围内
that condition, that Markovian condition will probably apply.
马尔可夫链条件可能可以成立
But if you are on a very large image, the whole image won't have a Markovian
但如果你在一个很大的图像上操作 整张图不会满足马尔可夫链条件
condition. So basically, in small regions you expect
就是说 小范围中假设可能成立
that assumption to hold, but it doesn't hold in large regions and it's not hard
但在很大范围中则不行
to see that. If you're just, let's say, looking at me
这并不难理解 譬如说 你现在正看着我
right now, you see that there's a lot of correlation here,, more or less the same
你会看到这里有很多相关性 灰度值几乎一样
gray values. But if you actually start moving away and
但如果向其它地方看
you say, is there a correlation between the pixel value here and the pixel value
这里和这里的像素离得这么远
here that they are very far away? There's actually no correlation.
这两个像素值之间有相关性吗？其实是没有的
I can actually change my shirt and without prior information. So there is no
我可以换一件衬衫 而不需要考虑之前的信息
correlation when you get far way in your image, pictures that are far away,
当你图中的像素离得很远的时候 其实它们就没有相关性了
basically they start being decorrelated. So you need to get to a compromise. On
它们就是不相关的 所以你需要折中选择
one side you want very small blocks because you want to be computation very
一方面你希望有很小的小块以实现高效计算
efficient. on, on the other hand basically you don't
另一方面你不希望小块太小
want too small blocks, because you get into, into this problem of not having
因为你会遇到这样的问题 小块中没有足够的信息
enough information in the block, enough correlation to be able to decorrelate
没有足够的关联性 在变换中会被去相关
with the transform. And if you get to two large blocks, you
如果你选了太大的模块
start paying computations, and you start paying that you violated the assumptions
你将要面对低效的计算 并且你忽视了 DCT 的优点的设定条件
for which the DCT is good. So 8 x 8 is a good that I say was, was,
你将为此付出代价 所以 8 × 8 是个不错的选择
was significantly studied and it got into a very, very good compromised and that's
我认为这是深入研究后很有意义的成果 它是很好的折中办法
why it used today for JPEG. So, to conclude this part of the DCT, I
这就是它如今被用在 JPEG 上的原因 作为对本部分离散余弦变换的介绍的总结
just want to show you once again this image, Lina. And these are just two
我想要再展示一次 Lena 的图像
different cases, but don't worry about that for the moment.
这是两个不同的例子 现在先不要担心它
Here, basically we took 8 x 8 plots, we did a DCT, and we kept 12.5% of their
这里 我们取用 8 × 8 模块 进行离散余弦变换 我们保留 12.5%的系数
coefficients, and then we came back. Not really quantization, which is going
然后我们进行逆变换 没有真正进行量化 那是我们下一步的内容
to be our next step, just a DCT and the inverse DCT.
这里我们只进行离散余弦变换和它的逆变换
And it looks pretty good than is, it just when we just look for the first time at
这看起来很不错 就是说 我们第一眼看到它时
the image, we actually have achieved compression, because we only kept 12.5%
我们已经成功压缩了 因为我们
of the pixels and we got an image which looks almost identical to the original
只保留了像素的12.5% 但得到了看起来和原图几乎一样的效果
one and that's because we did that in the DCT domain.
这是因为我们是在离散余弦变换的变换域中进行处理的
If we were to actually flow basically a lot of pixels here and keep only 12.5%,.
如果我们只是扔掉大量像素 只保留它的12.5%
we will not be able to get this quality of the image.
我们不能得到这样质量的图像
This is just the error between the original and the reconstructed.
这是原图和重建的图像之间的误差
And as you see, it's relatively small error.
可以看到 这是个很小的误差
So this is pretty good compression by nothing else than doing a DCT,
所以说单单一个离散余弦变换
basically removing a lot of coefficients and coming back.
去除大量系数 然后逆变换 就已经完成了相当不错的压缩
So now, we have the front end and we have the back end.
现在我们已经了解了前端和后端
What's missing is the middle. I'm in the DCT domain, can I achieve even
只差中间部分 我现在在 DCT域中
more compression by doing quantization in a smart fashion?
我能通过量化处理高明地实现更大程度的压缩么？
And that's going to be the subject of our next video clip.
这将是我们下一个视频的主题 // 果壳教育无边界字幕组 | 和风煦日 | leafsherry | Coowesome | wugui | 小白_远游